# Ricardo Cisneros

Desert Hot Springs, CA 92240 9095194582 – ricardocisneros197@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricardo-cisneros-5b8b3024b">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricardo-cisneros-5b8b3024b</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/ricardoci">https://github.com/ricardoci</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://reactportfolio22.herokuapp.com/">https://reactportfolio22.herokuapp.com/</a>

\_\_\_\_\_

### Summary

Full Stack Developer who is passionate about continuously expanding my skill set and keeping up to date with the latest technologies. Knowledge of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities with lots of on hand experience.

### Skills

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap

\_\_\_\_\_

Experience

Full Stack Application Jason Byers

03/2023 - 03/2023

Remote

https://targetsearchapp.herokuapp.com/

- Discussed project progress with the client, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.
- Created a web application that allows users to search for Target property/store locations and obtain the address, city, state, and zip code of the location
- The application embeds a Google map into the page for each location searched.
- The application also contains sign up, sign in, log out, and guest functions to enhance user experience.

Warehouse Worker Target 02/2018 - Current Fontana, CA

- Outbound Shipping: sorting and organizing inventory, operating forklifts or other equipment, maintaining cleanliness and safety standards, and fulfilling orders accurately.
- ICQA Inventory Audits: Conducted regular inventory audits to verify stock levels and ensure accuracy. Utilized inventory management systems/tools to reconcile discrepancies, investigate root causes, and implement corrective actions.
- Sorter Operator and Tray Communication: Effectively operated sorting equipment and communicated tray usage, capacity, and recirculation rate.

Maintenance Ground Dignity Memorial

03/2017 - 10/2017 Bloomington, CA

## Ricardo Cisneros

- Operated excavators, tractors, and gators with proficiency after completing training programs for safe handling.
- Maintained park grounds, ensuring cleanliness and attractive appearance through tasks like moving lawns, trimming hedges, and planting flowers.
- Worked closely with colleagues to ensure timely preparations for funeral services, burials, and other arrangements.

Warehouse Worker Amazon 05/2015 - 5/2016 San Bernardino, CA

- maintaining cleanliness and safety standards, and fulfilling orders accurately.
- Assisted in packing live orders and managing inventory at Amazon Fresh.
- Helped identify and dispose of bad inventory to maintain quality standards and prevent customer dissatisfaction.

\_\_\_\_\_

### **Projects**

CryptoData | https://github.com/ricardoci/CryptoData | https://ricardoci.github.io/CryptoData/

- Use newly acquired skills to create an interactive client-side application that utilizes third-party APIs and local storage. This application should be able to accept and respond to user input.
- My responsibilities in this project included setting up a fetch call to the API, implementing a watchlist feature to save desired currency data in local storage, and styling the application.

SkyCast | https://ricardoci.github.io/WeatherForecastApp/ | https://github.com/ricardoci/WeatherForecastApp

- Utilized the Open Weather API and displayed objects to the front end
- Implemented local storage functionality to store users' search history, enabling convenient access to weather information without the need to rewrite the search query.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development- University of Minnesota

St.Paul, MN

Riverside City College: 2yrs - Computer Science

Riverside, CA